# Prajwal Ale

A: Broadmeadows VIC, 3047 T: 0450 590 994

E: aleprajwal@gmail.com LinkedIn Profile: <u>in/aleprajwal</u>

# **Career Objective**

A recent graduate with a Master of Information Technology (Cybersecurity) from Charles Sturt University and 2 years of experience in a customer service role. Gained ITILv4 Foundation and AWS Cloud Practitioner certificate to demonstrate commitment to the industry and enhance technical ability. I'm looking for a full-time IT Graduate role where I can utilize my customer service skill and solidify my technical knowledge into skills to support clients and customers.

## **Technical Skills**

Office Package: Office 365, MS Teams, SharePoint, Outlook

**Operating System:** Windows 7, 10, Windows Server 2016, Ubuntu Linux,

MacOS

**Remote Support tools:** TeamViewer, Remote Desktop Connection, Zoom

Helpdesk Ticketing System: Gepard, Zendesk

**Active Directory:** User and password management, group policy

Virtualization: Virtualbox, VMWare Hypervisor Scripting and Programming: Python, SQL, Javascript, HTML, CSS Cloud Computing: Amazon Web Services, Azure

## **Education**

Professional Year Dec 2022 - Present

Performance Education, Melbourne

Key Subjects: Australian Business Culture and Environment, Achieving Career Success, Australian Workplace Skills and Professional Business Communication

### Master of Information Technology (Cybersecurity)

Mar 2020 - Nov 2021

Charles Sturt University, Melbourne Study Center

Key Subjects: Dark web, Information Security, Digital Forensics, Cloud Computing, System Analysis

# **Bachelor of Computer Engineering**

Oct 2014 - Aug 2018

National College of Engineering, Lalitpur Nepal

Key Subjects: Computer Networks, Internet and Intranet, Data Structures, and Algorithms, Software Engineering, Data Mining

# **University Project**

# AWS IT Lab Implementation

Mar 2021 - Apr 2021

Charles Sturt University, Melbourne

**Objective:** Creating an IT Lab to deploy Virtual Public Cloud (VPC) on AWS with a private

and public subnet

**Tools:** AWS Educate, EC2 Instance, NAT Instance

**Duties:** The project was divided into multiple milestones: creating VPC with a public

and private subnet, deploying EC2 instance and launching Windows server,

and deploying WordPress and database instance.

**Outcome:** Launched a running cloud-based IT lab with a live Windows server serving

database and WordPress instance

**Result:** Obtained Credit for this project

## DDoS Attack IDS Using ML/DL Technique

Jul 2021 - Oct 2021

Charles Sturt University, Melbourne

**Objective:** AA quantitative evaluation of a deep learning based intrusion detection

system for DDoS attack

**Tools:** Python Programming language, Deep Learning Technique, Jupyter Notebook

**Duties:** As a part of an individual project, I completed the research project by

breaking it down into multiple milestones. I broke down the project into the preliminary research and understanding stage, data collection stage, data processing stage, model building stage, training and testing stage, and

research documentation stage

**Outcome:** The research project concluded deep learning technique is a prospective use

case for an intrusion detection system for DDoS attacks. The result showed 99% accuracy in binary classification and 80.2% in multi-class classification

**Result:** Obtained Credit for this project

# **Personal Project**

# **Face Detection App**

View Source Code

A computer vision based application that can detect faces on a live feed video. It utilises prebuilt light weigh face detection model called haarcascade.

#### **PizzaBot**

View Source Code

A chatbot that helps to take online orders from a customer. Its objective was to automate drivethru customer service. It was built using the google Dialogflow tool that utilised backend webhook written in python programming language.

# **Head Cropping Tool**

View Source Code View Demo

A computer vision based tool that automatically crops head from an image.

# **Employment History**

## **Barista / Front of House**

May 2022 - Present

The League of Honest Coffee, Melbourne

- Delivering customer service by managing a weekly average of 600 guest arrivals, processing payments, noting requests, and resolving issues
- Receiving more than 25 telephone calls and in-person requests for information, and order placement
- Adding value to the café brand by demonstrating continuous improvement in the barista skills
- Supervising and training new staff to smoothly transition to their responsibilities

# **Web Developer Intern**

Iul 2022 - Oct 2022

Sharp Circles, Melbourne

- Researched on usability and accessibility-focused website design to redesign company's website
- Designed and developed websites using WordPress and optimized for performance and search engines
- Developed user interfaces using wireframes and frontend tools: HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Communicated regularly with the mentor and clients to meet desired requirements
- Observed, participated in, and contributed to team meetings and followed agile practices

## **Software Developer Intern**

Jan 2019 - Jun 2019

Eepos IT Holdings Nepal, Kathmandu NP

- Developed a chatbot using Dialogflow that automated more than 25 common queries and receive users' information
- Implemented API for common chatbot responses using Flask framework and deployed in Google App Engine
- Labeled over 500 image datasets using Labelbox application to improve the ML classifier model
- Implemented a web scraper tool to fetch data from over 20 websites using the Scrapy library
- Collaborated in a team to find an optimal solution to the client's requirement following agile software development methodology

## **Personal Attributes**

- Excellent interpersonal skills, as demonstrated through 2 years of experience in customer service
- Strong time management and organizational skills developed through 6 years of successfully combining work and university studies
- Reliability and accountability towards my job responsibility, contributing to the efficient business workflow at the workplace

#### References

Available upon request